There Was Never Just One
The Bourne Legacy is a action, thriller film directed by Tony Gilroy.
New CIA operative Aaron Cross experiences life-or-death stakes that have
been triggered by the previous actions of Jason Bourne.
Aaron Cross, played by Jeremy Renner.
Dr. Marta Shearing, played by Rachel Weisz.
Byer, played by Edward Norton.
Turso, played by Stacy Keach.
Ward, played by Dennis Boutsikaris.
Outcome #3, played by Oscar Isaac.
The Bourne Legacy is a 2012 American action-thriller film directed by Tony Gilroy,
who wrote the story and co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Dan.
It is the fourth installment in the Bourne series of films following The Bourne
Ultimatum (2007), which was adapted from the Jason Bourne novels.
It stars Jeremy Renner as Aaron Cross, alongside Rachel Weisz,
Edward Norton, Stacy Keach, and Oscar Isaac.
The film follows Aaron Cross, a black ops agent and a member of Operation Outcome, whose subjects are genetically enhanced, and must run for his life
once former CIA assassin Jason Bourne's actions lead to the exposure of Operation Treadstone, and its successor, Operation Blackbriar.
The Bourne Legacy is the only film in the franchise that does not feature titular character Jason
Bourne, as actor Matt Damon chose not to return because Paul Greengrass was not the director.
Bourne is shown in pictures and mentioned by name
several times throughout the film.
Tony Gilroy, co-screenwriter of the first three films, sought to continue the story of the film series without changing its key
events, and parts of The Bourne Legacy take place at the same time as the previous film, The Bourne Ultimatum (2007).
Filming was primarily in New York City, with some scenes shot
in the Philippines, South Korea, and Canada.
The Bourne Legacy premiered in New York City on July 30, 2012, and was later
theatrically released on August 10, in the United States by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office success,
grossing $280 million on a budget of $125 million.
The film explores themes of assassin, espionage,
wolf, maryland, covert operation.
The tone is intense.